Guide to the Henry Geldzahler Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- December 1999 Acquisition, circa 1945-1996; 1; 39.04; (43 boxes)
  - Six audiocassettes, 1983-1988 (Box 14, Folder 8.28)
    1) Geldzahler/Tamasburo interview, 7 May 1984 - Japage Kabuki Master, published in Interview magazine; 2) Geldzahler, 19 January 1988. Unidentified lecture; 3) Geldzahler lecture, 9 February 1983, Lowe Art Museum; 4) Geldzahler interview with D. Hockney, 20 January 1985; 5) Geldzahler and I.M. Pei, 12 June 1985 - Elle magazine; 6) Geldzahler interview with Alice Neel, 27 June 1984, "Interview No. 2".
  - Shoe box containing approximately 100 items from Horace Mann School and before, including school essays and correspondence, 5 (Box 14, Folder 8.29)
  - Henry's huge blue binder from The Metropolitan Museum containing clippings of Matisse sculpture [materials removed from binder, binder discarded], 4 (Box 14, Folder 8.3)
  - Photographs, circa 1945-1986; 5 (Box 14, Folder 8.31)
    1) 5 B&W photos of Frank Stella paintings, 1959; 2) 3 B&W photos of Hockney drawings; 3) Several B&W photos and negatives of head of Roman sculpture of Antinous; 4) Bundle of color and B&W photos of Henry, family, friends dating from late 40's to 70's; 5) One envelope marked "Great Grandparents" containing one large B&W negative; 6) Stack of photos, color and B&W including pictures of Henry with family, young relatives, art people, alone, portraits, with Warhol, etc.; 7) 7 photos from Venice Biennale, incl. photos of Isamu Noguchi, circa 1986; 8) Stack of envelopes containing color photos (Iran ?) and color negatives of photos.
  - Photographs, mostly B&W 8x10 that are mostly early photos of relatives, many portraits, some later photos of Henry (Box 15, Folder 8.32)
  - David Hockney photos. Large B&W photos of DH's drawings, dozens of snapshot color shots of David and Henry and their travels, much in DH's California studio, including 8x10 color shot of Henry and Raymond Foye in studio next to unfinished DH portrait of them. Several beautifully composed photos by Hockney, 3 (Box 15, Folder 8.33)
  - Photographs (Box 15, Folder 8.34)
    1) One envelope mostly color of Henry and Randy Hunt, in Bali, photos taken by Hockney; 2) Stack of four envelopes of Iran photos, Royaltone bonus "double" prints, about envelopes; 3) Stack of envelopes with early photos and negatives, most of them marked, several from Ship Bottom; 4) Envelope of miscellaneous some taken by Warhol, others from Henry's travels, 1960's.
  - Unsorted material, 1962-1981 (Box 15, Folder 8.35)
    1) Yale, May 1968 Alumni bulletin; 2) Scribbled notes on Metropolitan Museum notepaper; 3) Peter Voulkos, 1981 exhibition announcement; 4) Small poster announcing Robert Berg exhibit, San Diego; 5) Postcard announcing Philip Pearlstein Show, 1981; 6) Announcement for John McKendry memorial service, 1976; 7) Four color photos including 2 pictures of Divine, 2 of Hockney; 8) Press release from The Land Press, London, 1980; 9) Clipping from NY Times of Henry's letter to the editor, 24 January 1980; 10) Clipping of face of Cornelius from "Planet of the Apes." 11) Envelope with four slides from Michael Hurson; 12) 31 July 1979 letter from Philip Tarlowith 13) 16 May 1979 postcard from Raymond Foye in Hawaii; 14) 8 May 1979 postcard from Raymond Foye in San Francisco; 15) 20 August 1979 letter from Raymond Foye in San Francisco; 16) Ray Gun Theatre postcard schedule, 1962 ©. Oldenburg); 17) 13 June 1962 letter from James J. Rorimer; 18) 26 May 1978 letter and photo of Henry from Benita; 19) Grey Art Gallery Bulletin, Henry on cover, 1981; 20) Postcard from Basil Langton with color slide of Henry and D. Hockney attached; 21) 20 May 1979 letter from Raymond Foye in Hawaii; 22) 12 November 1979 letter from Raymond Foye in purple ink; 23) 7 May 1979 postcard from Raymond Foye in San Francisco; 24) 26 September 1978 letter from Eugene Draper; 25) 3 June 1979 letter from Eugene Draper; 26) Announcement of photo show by Vivienne Maricevic, 1979 with note from Vivienne, and note from Eugene Draper; 27) Undated letter from Eric Sackheim in Tokyo; 28) 18 May 1979 postcard from Raymond Foye in Bali; 29) 22 June 1979 letter from Eugene Draper; 30) 8 June 1979 letter from Raymond Foye in San Francisco; 31) Clipping from Art People column of Ellsworth Kelly; 32) Bundle of clippings from 1980 Summer Philharmonic.
  - Unidentified photographs (Box 15, Folder 8.36)
  - Enrique Castro- Cid - Notes for DIA catalogue (Box 15, Folder 9.1)
  - Scavullo - Copy of his article on Geldzahler (Box 15, Folder 9.2)
  - John Chamberlain: DIA 1992, notes on new work; notes and drafts of interview for Pace Gallery; clippings regarding Show at DIA (Box 15, Folder 9.3)
  - Alice Neel: show at DIA; clippings; Thank You note from C. Wright; drafts of article in the catalogue (Box 15, Folder 9.4)
  - Prestini - Photos of works by Prestini (Box 15, Folder 9.5)
  - Roy Lichtenstein: notes and drafts for the piece, "Mural with Blue Brushstroke" for graphics (Box 15, Folder 9.6)
  - Nobu Fukui: notes and drafts for intro to the catalogue by Melrissa Del Rey (Box 15, Folder 9.7)
  - Louise Bourgoeise: notes and drafts for Interview mag (Box 15, Folder 9.8)
  - Jules Olitski: notes and drafts of interview for Salander O'Reilly catalogue (Box 15, Folder 9.9)
  - Articles: recent paintings by H. Hartung; Joseph Albers 1971; 1976; F. Bacon at the Met.; M. Hurson, October 1982; Ed Steichen, May 1961; Art News, 1961-1982 (Box 15, Folder 9.1)
  - Wallace Putnam: from estate offers for sale of W.P.'s works from estate (Box 15, Folder 9.11)
  - Andy Warhol: reviews of the show at DIA, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 9.12)
  - David Salle: notes and drafts for the book of photographs (Box 15, Folder 9.13)
  - Ignacio Salazar: notes and drafts on piece for Monterrey Museum (Box 15, Folder 9.14)
  - Francesco Clemente: notes and drafts for "Clemente in Basel" (Box 15, Folder 9.15)
  - Ellsworth Kelly: notes and drafts on works on paper; 27 Lithographs; review of the show at DIA 1991 (Box 15, Folder 9.16)
  - Jean Michel Basquiat: copy of interview for Interview Magazine (Box 15, Folder 9.17)
  - Jean Michel Basquiat: xeroxes of sketch and Notebooks from L. Warsh (Box 16, Folder 9.18)
  - Ascher Edelman: announcements for the talk at Museum in Laussane, Swiss (Box 16, Folder 9.19)
  - Charles Bell: notes and drafts monograph (Box 16, Folder 9.2)
  - Provincetown Magazine: draft of an article (Box 16, Folder 9.21)
  - Provincetown: request for help from P. Assoc. (Box 16, Folder 9.22)
  - Lecture at Guild Hall: notes and transcription (Box 16, Folder 9.23)
  - Copies of lectures (Box 16, Folder 9.24)
    1) Soho lecture - 5/15/75; 2) Museum of Modern Art lecture - 2/63; 3) VSIA lecture; 4) Interview for EKB "Made in NY" - 3/3/82; 5) The Influence of Criticism on Cont. Art, 1/69; 6) Putting the Arts to Work, 8/21/79; 7) Lecture at the Whitney Museum of American Art; 8) Cross-Pollination; European and American art; 9) Friends of Art Love Art Museum, 2/9/83; 10) Bennington lecture, 6/62; 11) Modern European painting and sculpture.
  - Discoveries VI: notes and drafts for Intro; Copy of catalogue (Box 16, Folder 9.25)
  - Tel Aviv Museum: regarding donation (Box 16, Folder 9.26)
  - Yale Speech: notes (actual folder # 25), 1992 March 19 (Box 16, Folder 9.27)
  - Long Island University: letter from Mr. Peterson (Box 16, Folder 9.28)
  - Stuart Davis: promo material for centennial (actual folder # 27) (Box 16, Folder 9.29)
  - Sao Paolo Bienale: clippings and photos (Box 16, Folder 9.3)
  - Ray Charles White: layout for graphics (actual folder # 29) (Box 16, Folder 9.31)
  - Billy Name: Interview with B.N. for Czech catalogue (actual folder # 30) (Box 16, Folder 9.32)
  - Reggie Cabral: proposition for show of Reggie Cabrals collection (actual folder # 31) (Box 16, Folder 9.33)
  - Andy Warhol's Movies: 2 page typescript, press release, Jan 1964; reprinted in Film Culture, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 10.1)
  - Museum Talk: 6 pages, carbon, on Demuth's "I Saw the Figure 5 in Gold" compared with Johns' Numbers (Box 16, Folder 10.2)
  - Modern European Painting and Sculpture: 20 page typescript essay (Box 16, Folder 10.3)
  - Frank Stella Interview: 9 pages recto and verso handwritten questions and responses in ink, Geldzahler's script and someone else's (probably Stella); 6 page typescript of same, with Geldzahler corrections in hand, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 10.4)
  - Times Op-Ed: 4 pages typescript, cut and pasted, on why NY needs another museum collecting 20th century art (Box 16, Folder 10.5)
  - Interview with Larry Poons: 5 pages typescript with a few corrections by hand (Box 16, Folder 10.6)
  - Andy Warhol essay: 3 page xeroxed typescript of essay for Swedish Museum Pop Art catalogue Jan 1964; 6 page carbon, an expanded version of the above with note "Published April '64 Art International" (Box 16, Folder 10.7)
  - Modern Art at the Metropolitan Museum of Art: 5 page carbon typescript, raison d'etre for Met collecting modern art (Box 16, Folder 10.8)
  - Works Since 1966 (Box 16, Folder 10.9)
    "Chapter IX" with 4 pages of footnotes. 29 pages, typescript heavily edited by professional editor, some cutting pasting. The title refers to Jasper Johns' works since 1966 and deals extensively with Decoy, Passage I and II, Harlem Light, Wall Piece and Untitled (1972). The essay contains a great deal of personal insights drawn from the company and conversation of Johns.
  - 1966 Venice Biennale Lecture: Frankenthaler, Kelly, Olitski, Lichtenstein., 1966 May 17 (Box 16, Folder 10.1)
    30 pages, carbon typescript on onion skin paper, 2 copies heavily edited by Geldzahler, cut and pasted. Two additional xeroxed copies. A cover letter from John Latham at Smithsonian thanking Geldzahler for the lecture.
  - Miscellaneous Writings, circa 1966 (Box 16, Folder 10.11)
    23 pages, a variety of stray lecture notes and writings on art and artists, circa 1964-1966, some dealing with the Sao Paolo Biennale of 1966.
  - The Audience for Art: 4 page typescript with Geldzahler emendations. Published in the Hudson Review, circa 1964 (Box 16, Folder 10.12)
  - Venice and Sao Paolo Biennale: 51 pages, typescript and handwritten notes and text, heavily edited and pasted up, by Geldzahler. Working drafts of his essays on the Venice and Sao Paolo Biennales (Box 16, Folder 10.13)
  - Venice and Sao Paolo Biennale, 1966 (Box 16, Folder 10.14)
    1) 7 pages handwritten notes on V.B.; 2) 19 page typescript heavily edited and pasted; 3) 28 page carbon on onion skin: the finished essay; 4) 18 page as above; 5) 1 page typescript, 16 pages handwritten (not in Geldzahler's hand) draft; 6) 9 pages mostly typed draft some handwritten by editor; 7) 15 pages 8 ½ x 51/2" mostly handwritten editor's notes.
  - Photodeath and Ironworks: 9 page carbon typescript of Claes Oldenburg happenings Geldzahler acted in; with Geldzahler's pencilled notes about props, stage directions (Box 16, Folder 10.15)
  - Happenings and Films: Theater by Artists (Box 16, Folder 10.16)
    1) 2 pages typescript with a few corrections; 2) 1 page editor's notes; 3) 1 page Geldzahler handwritten notes titled "Expanded Cinema"; 4) xerox essay, final and 1 page original typescript draft.
  - Ellsworth Kelly, Jewish Museum, Toward A New Abstraction: 6 page typescript essay on EK, plus 6 page xerox of interview with EK, from Dec 1963; 2 page typescript with hand corrections; statement on Ellsworth Kelly,1966, 1963-1966 (Box 16, Folder 10.17)
  - Léger: 4 page typescript, review of forthcoming Leger show at Guggenheim, 1962 February (Box 16, Folder 10.18)
  - Twenty-one Questions for Roy Lichtenstein: 1 page handwritten notes by Geldzahler, on verso of a Café Figaro flier (Box 16, Folder 10.19)
  - "The Art Education of the Painter": 28 page heavily edited and pasted typescript (Box 16, Folder 10.2)
  - Robert Rauschenberg: 7 page carbon typescript, review of RR show at Jewish Museum, Art International, 1962 September (Box 16, Folder 10.21)
  - Lecture Notes: 22 half pages, handwritten lecture notes (in Geldzahler's hand), circa 1964 (Box 16, Folder 10.22)
  - George Segal: 5 page typescript of interview, pub in Art Forum, September 1964; 4 page carbon typescript on onion skin, essay on Segal for Jewish Museum Report, October 1964 (Box 16, Folder 10.23)
  - USIA and UNESCO Lectures (Box 16, Folder 10.24)
    1) USIA Lecture: Ab Exp and their inheritors; 8 page pasted up typescript with corrections by hand; 2) UNESCO World Art Series, 4 page original typescript, pasted and hand corrected by Geldzahler; 3) final draft of above: 5pages, typescript and two carbons.
  - Miscellaneous Writings (Box 16, Folder 10.25)
    1) 10 pages (5 ½ x 8 ½") handwritten notes by Geldzahler's asst.; 2) 4 pages (5 ½ x 8 ½") handwritten notes by Geldzahler; 3) 1 page typescript and carbon: Statement on the Avant-Garde; 4) 3 page handwritten (by Geldzahler asst) listing of slide comparisons, for a lecture in Pasadena, April 21, 1966; 5) 1 page typescript, "An Interdisciplinary Proposal" regarding Merce Cunningham Co.; 6) 2 page memo, typescript heavily corrected by Geldzahler, on the role and aim of the Jewish Museum; 7) 1 page typescript, statement on Warhol; 8) 1 page typescript, vitae of Burgoyne Diller.
  - National Endowment for the Arts: letters and memos from Geldzahler to Roger Stevens, on NEA budget; reports on Visual Arts programs and budgets; approximately 100 pages, 1967-1968 (Box 16, Folder 10.26)
  - States Arts Councils: letters, memos and reports. approximately 150 pages (Box 16, Folder 10.27)
  - Artist's Housing: 6 page typescript by Geldzahler on NEA visual arts program; letters, memos, reports mostly with artists-tenant assoc. on early days of artist's loft living in NYC, approximately 50 pages (Box 16, Folder 10.28)
  - NEA: House bills, Congressional testimony, Congressional Record extract, some correspondence, approximately 40 pages (Box 16, Folder 10.29)
  - NEA: Memos, correspondence to and from Geldzahler on a wide variety of NEA-related topics, Detroit Institute of Arts, Northern Texas Resources Council, Inter-American Foundation for the Arts, approximately 300 pages (Box 16, Folder 10.3)
  - NEA: Lists, letters, memos on direct fellowships to artists program. Typescript letter signed by Motherwell with postscript, autograph manuscript letter signed by Diebenkorn, approximately 30 pages (Box 16, Folder 10.31)
  - NEA: Proposal from Allan Kaprow on "An Institute for Experimentation in the Arts" 16 pages, with handwritten note in margin of report by AK; Literary Magazine Proposal, 2 pages; reports and letters regarding Visual Arts Committee; grants-in-aid to museums (Box 16, Folder 10.32)
  - NEA: correspondence and proposals from Tatyana Grosman at Universal Art Editions Ltds, regarding NEA grant to install etching facilities; grants proposal for sculptor's experimentation (Box 16, Folder 10.33)
  - Letters: File Boxes A - F, G - Z (Box 16, Folder 10.34)
    Including Mario Amaya, John Baldessari, Gregory Batcock, Thomas Hart Benton (xerox; original in Museum of Modern Art archives), Enrique Castro-Cid, Sally and Wynn Chamberlain, John Coplans, Merce Cunningham, Dan Flavin, Helen Frakenthaler, Barnett Newman, Tanya Grosman, John Giorno, R.Philip Hanes, Jr., Will Insley, Mark Lancaster, Claes and Patty Oldenburg, Bob Skull, Richard Smith, Ambassador and Mrs Stanley Woodward, LaMonte Young, Michael Zimmer
  - Archives of American Art Interview: 53 pages, typed, interview with Geldzahler by Paul Cummings; a comprehensive overview of Geldzahler's family background, youth, education and career up to 1970, 1970 January 27 (Box 17, Folder 10.35)
  - Unidentified interview: typescript, paginated 21-60. Interview with Geldzahler about the Warhol scene, 1973 May 10 (Box 17, Folder 10.36)
  - Memoirs: Outline: 3 page handwritten outline dictated by Geldzahler, plus cover letter from Andrew Wylie, his literary agent (Box 17, Folder 10.37)
  - Art In Embassies Program: 5 pages correspondence to Geldzahler on 25th Anniversary symposium, AIE program, Department of State (Box 17, Folder 10.38)
  - Hanuman Books: Small press run by R. Foye and F. Clemente, publisher of Geldzahler's "Looking at Pictures." 3 early catalogues, 2 postcards from RF in India, 1990 (Box 17, Folder 11.1)
  - Hamptons Artists: Eleven Painters catalogs Guild Hall, east Hampton, with autograph manuscript letter from Robert long thanking Geldzahler for an interview (Box 17, Folder 11.2)
  - Exhibition Ideas File: 10 pages typed and handwritten, various ideas for shows and lists of artists (Box 17, Folder 11.3)
  - Method in Kelly, Lichtenstein and Stella: 15 pages, typed and handwritten notes for an exhibition proposal for Larry Rubin at Knoedler Gallery (Box 17, Folder 11.4)
  - A Few Notes on the Power of Childhood: 2 page original typed manuscript, statement on exhibition curated at Wessel O'Connor gallery, curated by Wickham Boyle, plus gallery handout with printed statement (Box 17, Folder 11.5)
  - "Ego File" (Geldzahler's label) Eleven jotted notes on post-it paper; 5 page typescript "Biographical Information" hand corrected by Geldzahler; Who's Who entry, 1978; plus various press clippings, 1978-1992 (Box 17, Folder 11.6)
    1) "La Passion de l'art," article on Geldzahler in Monde, with photo 8 March 1992, 2 copies; 2) "The Curator as Celebrity: Geldzahler Mirrored his Artists, Christian Science Monitor, 16 March 1992, interview and article by Anne Lloyd Wilson; 3) "At The Galleries" Southampton Press Oct 22, 1987 review of Geldzahler show of Wallace Putnam paintings at DIA Bridgehampton; 4) "Mad Hatter," Southampton Press, 4/26/90, article with photos on Geldzahler as judge of Mad Hatter's Ball at Parrish Art Museum; 5) "From the Studio," The East Hampton Star, 9/22/88 review of Geldzahler's Costantin Nivola show at DIA Bridgehampton; 6) New York Times 8/5/90, review of Myron Stout exhib cur by Geldzahler at DIA Bridgehampton; 7) "Geldzahler, The Talent Hunter," English trans of article in O Estado (Brazil?).
  - Warhol: Subject/Object (Box 17, Folder 11.7)
    1) Approximately twenty-five 5 x 7 index cards containing lecture notes; another packet of handwritten notes on twelve index cards and note pages, on Warhol as portraitist; 2) thirty-one pages handwritten notes on Warhol for text, "Andy Warhol: Virginal Voyeur," (Thames and Hudson, 1993); 3) xerox of galleys of above-mentioned text; 4) extensive press file of notices, clippings, articles from various Australian newspapers, covering Geldzahler's lectures and appearances in Australia, 1994.
  - Memorandum to the Warhol Museum, Pittsburgh: 6 pages, typed; forty-one topics and ideas for exhibitions, lectures and auditorium events., 1992 (Box 17, Folder 11.8)
  - Australia lecture tour: Press materials, itineraries, letters and correspondence relating to Geldzahler's 1994 visit, circa 1994 (Box 17, Folder 11.9)
  - Sydney's Cultural Future. 4 pages handwritten notes (5 x 7") for lecture, 1994 February 22 (Box 17, Folder 11.1)
  - Party People: 2 legal pages handwritten names and telephone numbers (Box 17, Folder 11.11)
  - Miscellaneous: "Lecture on Quality" Fifteen handwritten pages of notes; "Looking at Pictures" faxed galleys to Geldzahler's Hanuman book, with Henry's corrections and cuts in red ink; 1 page typescript with hand corrections, Geldzahler's editorial additions to the above-mentioned text (Box 17, Folder 11.12)
  - Art in Embassies (Box 17, Folder 11.13)
    1) Remarks on the 25th Anniversary of the Art in Embassies Program. 2 pages, typescript, Geldzahler's reflections on the Woodward Foundation; 2) 4 pages "Correspondence and Attachments"; 3) "Art in Embassies 25th Anniversary Symposium: The Role of American Art in the International Arena." 77 page typed transcript, including Geldzahler, Andre Emmerich, John L Marion, Richard Olenburg, Norman Rosenthal, Rauschenberg, moderated by Grace Glueck; 4) Inventory of works of art owned by Woodward Foundation, with acquisition prices.
  - "Knowing Artists" Lecture at Horowitz Theatre, Edmonton, Alberta: 9 pages of handwritten lecture notes; personal letters from hosts and local artists, and photos of visit to Alberta, 25 items (Box 17, Folder 11.14)
  - Horace Mann Speech: 3 pages handwritten lecture notes to students at Horace Mann prep school (Box 17, Folder 11.15)
  - Provincetown Lecture: memoir of the Provincetown scene in the early 1960s, and general reflection on art and artists, 1991 December 14 (Box 17, Folder 11.16)
    1) 20 legal pages, handwritten lecture notes; 2) 17 index cards, 5 x 7", lecture notes; 3) 40 page typed lecture transcript heavily corrected in red ink in Geldzahler's hand; 4) 40 page lecture transcript, typed, incorporating Geldzahler's editing.
  - What I know About Photography: lecture at the Monterrey Museum, Mexico, 1992 May 14 (Box 17, Folder 11.17)
    1) 19 pages handwritten lecture notes; 2) 31 (5 x 7") index cards with handwritten lecture notes; 3) 20 page typed transcript with Geldzahler's corrections in blue ink; 4) another copy with correction in red ink by Geldzahler; 5) another copy with corrections in pencil by Geldzahler; 6) various press notices and photos of the event, some bound in an event book.
  - Modern Art in America (Box 17, Folder 11.18)
    1) Approximately 40 pages handwritten notes on legal pages, including lists of comparative illustrations; 2) Approximately 40 pages typescript, extensive biographical info, notes and quotes on and by John Quinn, The Armory Show A.E. Gallatin, Gleizes, Duchamp, Picabia, Man Ray, Paul Strand, Berenice Abbott. Much of this compiled by RF and Jonathan Weinberg under Geldzahler's direction; 3) early chapter of this book, with corrections in Geldzahler's hand.
  - Modern Art in America: first 7 chapters, 146 pages typescript. From 1870s through WPA and 1930s Regionalism. (Box 17, Folder 11.19)
  - David Hockney (Box 17, Folder 11.2)
    1) "David Hockney, Younger and Older" 17 page xerox of heavily edited draft of this essay. Most marks by Abrams editor, a few orig emendations by Geldzahler. Written for LACMA Retrospective catalogue; 2) "Hockney as Young Man" 17 page xerox, heavily edited, version of above, dated 3/9/87; 3) "Hockney at Fifty" 10 pages orig typescript with heavy editing in Geldzahler's hand, written for British Vogue; 4) "Hockney and Houses" article for House and Garden magazine; approximately 20 pages of original typescript heavily edited in Geldzahler's hand with cut and pasting 5) "Hockney and Houses" article for House and Garden magazine, approximately 12 pages xeroxes of drafts of above; 6) Listing of Hockney graphics owned by Geldzahler, with prices; 7) Hockney Younger and Older. The original of item (1) with numerous post-it notes in margin by editor.
  - David Hockney: Hockney Younger and Older. xerox of corrected galleys; correspondence and drafts regarding House and Garden and British Vogue articles (Box 17, Folder 11.21)
  - The Sixties Reseen in 1991 (Lecture): 21 pages, handwritten lecture notes; 46 page transcript of lecture with Geldzahler's orig corrections; 31 page transcript, heavily edited by Geldzahler in red and black ink; 31 page transcript, typed. The corrected version of above. (Box 17, Folder 11.22)
  - Bibliographies: approximately 30 pages of lists of writings by Geldzahler (Box 17, Folder 11.23)
  - Op-Ed piece: 5 pages original typescript with edits in Geldzahler's hand, on the subject of museum patronage. Written for NY Newsday. Unpublished, 1992 January 21 (Box 17, Folder 11.24)
  - Marcus Cafferty: extensive file on younger painter Marcus Cafferty (Box 17, Folder 11.25)
  - Myron Stout: Pathways and Epiphanies (Box 17, Folder 11.26)